Up until this point you've been launching nodes using the venerable Rosrun command.
迄今为止 你都在使用传统的 rosrun 命令启动节点
As I mentioned previously,
我前面讲过
a Ros system usually consists of many running nodes.
ROS 系统通常包括很多运行中的节点
Running all of the nodes by hand though can be torturous.
但手动运行所有节点可能非常麻烦
This is where the roslaunch command comes to save the day.
这时候 我们就需要 roslaunch 命令来救场了
Roslaunch allows you to launch multiple nodes with one simple command,
Roslaunch 允许你使用一个命令启动多个节点
set default parameters in the pram server,
在参数服务器中设置默认参数
automatically respond processes that have died and more.
自动回应已经关闭的进程等等
To use roslaunch, you must first make
要使用 roslaunch 你首先必须
sure that your work space has been built and sourced.
确保你已经搭建并提供了工作空间
Recall, to build the work space,
记住 要搭建工作空间
you use the command catkin_make while you're in the root of the work space.
你必须在工作空间根目录下使用 catkin_make 命令
So, let's move to the root of the work space
现在 我们移动到工作空间根目录
and let's issue the build command, catkin_make.
我们输入搭建命令 catkin_make
Once the work space has been built,
工作空间搭建完成后
you can source its set up script.
你就可以编写设置脚本了
The set up script lives in
设置脚本
the newly created directory devel in the root of the work space.
位于工作空间根目录下创建的 devel 目录下
In the same fashion as the setup.bash script in the OPT Ros directory,
和 OPT Ros 目录下的 setup.bash 脚本一样
the work space is setup.bash is responsible for setting up the environment variables,
Setup.bash 里的工作空间负责设置环境变量
which are responsible for letting the system find all of the packages,
方便系统找到你的 catkin 工作空间提供的
libraries and other resources provided by your catkin work space.
所有包、库和其他资源
So let's go ahead and source that now.
现在 我们开始编写
With your work space sourced,
工作空间完成后
you can now launch simple arm.
你就可以启动简单的机器臂了
To do so, use the command roslaunch,
具体操作为 使用命令 roslaunch
followed by the package name rossimple_arm and then the name of the launch file.
后面是包名称 rossimple_arm 然后是启动文件名称
And here, I'm just going to use tab completion robot_spawn.launch.
这里 我只需使用 tab completion robot_spawn.launch
Awesome. There we go. I've launched the arm
太棒了 就这样 我已经启动了机器臂
using the launch file and the simple arm package.
借助启动文件和简单机器臂包
A number of things just happened.
刚刚发生了几件事情
Perhaps the most apparent is that,
或许最明显的是
I now have a robotic arm running in simulation.
现在 我在仿真中有一个机器臂正在运行
The simulator is called gazebo.
仿真器叫做 gazebo
You continue to use it many times throughout this program.
你会在本学位中多次使用它
It is our surrogate for the real world,
它是我们在真实世界的替代品
it's responsible for simulating forces and torques,
负责仿真力和扭矩
the passage of time,
时间流逝
as well as interactions between objects such as collisions.
以及物体之间的互动 如撞击
The robot I'm simulating here is a simple two degree of freedom robotic arm.
我在这里仿真的机器人是一个简单的两度的自由机器手臂
It's perhaps hard to tell but there is a little black ball on the end of the arm.
机器臂的莫额为有一个黑色小球 可能很难看清楚
The ball represents a camera.
这个球代表摄像头
Gazebo can also simulate a wide variety of sensors.
Gazebo 也可以仿真很多不同传感器
It's not just gazebo that's running though.
但正在运行的不仅仅是 gazebo
If you switch over to the console window and scroll up,
如果你切换到控制台窗口并向上滚动
you can see that roslaunch has provided
你可以看到 roslaunch 提供了
the brief summary of all of the nodes which have been launched,
所有已启动节点的一个简短摘要
and all of the parameters which have been set.
以及所有已设置参数的小结
I won't spend any time talking about all the details of
我不会花时间讨论启动文件的
the launch file here but I encourage you to check it out.
所有细节 但我觉得你们应该检查一下
It's in the launch directory within the simple arm package.
它位于简单机器臂包的 launch 目录下
Now, that you understand how to create a work space,
现在 你已经知道了如何创建一个工作空间
add a package, build and launch everything,
添加一个包 搭建并启动所有东西
you're prepared for the next step,
接下来 我们学习后续步骤
figuring out why the arm is just swinging around loosely in simulation.
找出为什么机器臂在仿真中转动比较松弛的原因
While I'll be explaining it thoroughly in the next section,
我会在下一节详细介绍
I encourage you to try to figure it out before I spill the beans.
但我仍然鼓励你在听我讲解前自己发现原因
Here's a hint. Check the log messages in the ros master console.
小提示： 在 ros 主控制台上检查日志消息